The end of the road begins.
Fast X is a action, crime, thriller film directed by Louis Leterrier.
Over many missions and against impossible odds, Dom Toretto and his family have
outsmarted, out-nerved and outdriven every foe in their path.
Now, they confront the most lethal opponent they've ever faced: A terrifying threat emerging from the shadows of the past who's fueled by
blood revenge, and who is determined to shatter this family and destroy everything—and everyone—that Dom loves, forever.
Dominic Toretto, played by Vin Diesel.
Letty, played by Michelle Rodriguez.
Roman, played by Tyrese Gibson.
Tej, played by Ludacris.
Jakob, played by John Cena.
Ramsey, played by Nathalie Emmanuel.
Fast X (also known as Fast & Furious 10) is a 2023 American action film directed by Louis Leterrier from a
screenplay by Dan Mazeau and Justin Lin, both of whom also co-wrote the story with Zach Dean.
The sequel to F9 (2021), it is the tenth main installment and the
eleventh installment overall in the Fast & Furious franchise.
It stars Vin Diesel as Dominic Toretto, alongside Michelle Rodriguez, Tyrese Gibson, Ludacris, John Cena, Nathalie Emmanuel, Jordana Brewster, Sung Kang,
Scott Eastwood, Daniela Melchior, Alan Ritchson, Helen Mirren, Brie Larson, Rita Moreno, Jason Statham, Jason Momoa, and Charlize Theron.
In the film, Toretto must protect his family from Dante Reyes (Momoa), who
pursues revenge for his father's death and the loss of their fortune.
Development on a tenth main Fast & Furious film began by
October 2020, with Lin returning to direct.
The film's official title was revealed when
principal photography began in April 2022.
Lin left as director later that month, citing creative differences,
though he retained writing and producing credits.
Leterrier was then hired as his replacement a week later and
performed several uncredited rewrites to the screenplay.
Longtime franchise composer Brian Tyler returned to score the film.
With an estimated net production budget of $378.8 million, Fast
X is the sixth-most expensive film ever made.
Filming lasted until that August, taking place in
London, Rome, Turin, Lisbon, and Los Angeles.
Fast X premiered in Rome on May 12, 2023, and was released in the
United States on May 19, by Universal Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for its action
sequences and Momoa's performance but criticism towards the writing.
It grossed $714 million worldwide, becoming the
fifth-highest-grossing film of 2023.
A sequel that reportedly serves as the final main installment is in
development and is scheduled to be released in April 2027.
The film explores themes of sequel, revenge, betrayal, racing, family.
The tone is intense.